

# André Ibarra Pérez

Mobile + Web Developer

# **CONTACT**

- **831 113 1562**
- ☑ ibarraandre98@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/ibarraandre
- ibarraandre98.github.io
- Tamaulipas, México

# **EDUCATION**

# Instituto Tecnológico Superior de El Mante

Computer Systems Engineering August 2016 - June 2020

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Android Studio (Kotlin, Java)
Typescript
HTML - CSS
C#
Ionic & Angular
Node.js
SQL Server, MySQL, SQLite
Firebase & Supabase

#### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish - Native English - B1

# **SKILLS**

Innovation
Autonomy
Teamwork
Initiative
Self-taught
Proactive
Problem-solving
Leadership
Commitment

#### **ABOUT**

Software Developer with 3 years of professional experience in native mobile applications using Android Studio (Kotlin and Java), as well as over a year of experience in FrontEnd Web development (Angular).

Great analytical capacity to find solutions to the problems arise, responsibility, persistence, teamwork, self-taught, and a great ability to adapt quickly to changes, always seeking to achieve projects objectives efficiently, in addition to constantly updating myself learning development.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

NEORIS | Feb 2021 - Currently | Android, Angular and .NET

OXXO - mi OXXO App | Android and Angular Developer | June 2022 - Currently

- Creation of user interfaces and new functionalities implementation of products promotions and sales in the app, consumption of endpoints, View Model usage and local databases, and added HTTP calls interceptor, usage of Dagger and MVVM.
- Management, planning and development of a micro-website in Angular serving as a webview for the app, coding and consuming libraries functions in TypeScript from ecommerce and electronic payment and collection service provider.
- Implementation of user behavior analysis events, segmentation and functionalities capabilities, personalized messages per user, as well sending of push notifications using Amplitude, Leanplum, Facebook, Firebase and Salesforce (Interaction Studio, Marketing Cloud).
- Work and collaboration with different specialized teams in a few platforms to achieve development goals.
- Agile framework with SCRUM methodology, having daily monitoring by Scrum Master using JIRA.

Metals recycling company | Android Developer | June 2022 - July 2022

- Restructuring of the application architecture, modification of modules and endpoints consumption.
- Development of new modules with functionality such as QR codes reading.
- Code refactoring, bugs resolution and performance increase.
- Direct collaboration with American client, taking daily meetings as well deliverables English.

#### BBVA - Wibe App | Android Developer | March 2022 - June 2022

- Participation in development of an Android Kotlin mobile application that
  provides customizable insurance services for cars and motorcycles, coding new
  functionalities and creating auto insurance quotes and viewing their policies,
  endpoints consumption working with MVP.
- Optimization and creation of funcionalities with Google Services, Firebase, authentication, maps, places and location.
- Security analysis and stability in the production application. Teamwork with UX, backend and QA people to provide solutions for production bugs.
- Planning and management of application migration to Huawei OS Harmony using the Android Studio plugin "HMS Toolkit" and conducting manual testing (Google Services).

#### FEMSA - Comenzando Juntos | AngularJS and .NET Developer | March 2022 - Currently

- Management and control of a web application in AngularJS and development of new functionalities.
- Management, update and debugging of API in .NET, as well creation of Azure hosted webjobs running at specified intervals, and optimization of tables, foreign keys, columns, records and stored procedures in SQL Server database.
- · Collaboration and assistance with the team of mobile application which was also maintained by this API.

#### CEMEX - CEMEX Go Driver | Android Developer | May 2021 - January 2022

- Collaboration with the entire team in the development of user interfaces in a pair of mobile applications (Android Java and Kotlin), use of
  Google Services and dependency injection with Dagger, use of Google Services libraries for the development of geofencing functionalities and
  ticket development.
- · Coding of API's calls and implementation of offline functionalities with SQLite to the storage of received and pending data.
- Writing clean code following strict rules, as well as the use of MVVM.
- Development of new functionalities, use of geofences and conditionals based on parameters received at the time of login.

#### ARCA CONTINENTAL | Android Developer | February 2021 - April 2021

- Collaboration in the unification of three Android Java applications into one, modification of its architecture of the same one, neccesary coding to migration, using Dagger and management of local database with SQLite.
- Bugs resolution, schema modifications and flowchart changes.
- Removal of redundant and unnecessary code.

# Own Projects | May 2021 - April 2023 | Ionic, Angular, Node.js, MySQL and Supabase

#### Casa Blanca | Ionic Angular Developer and Backend Supabase | November 2022 - February 2023

- Full development of an Ionic and Angular mobile application from zero, for a company dedicated to providing pool and villa rental services for events, implementing functions such as display, creation, editing and deletion of events, exportation of events to word and excel, shortcut to sending whatsapps by client's phone number, searching filters by date ranges and text strings.
- Implementation of Supabase library to comunicate with backend services.
- Creation of a database in Supabase and it's respective routes to be consumed by the app, as well as security rules configurations based on roles to access to the API.
- Direct collaboration with the client, gathering their requirements, effective understanding of the business logic and its needs.
- · Successful launch of the application, subsequently adding more rental places for the client.

#### Provider Cranes Company | Ionic Angular Developer, Backend Node.js and MySQL | May 2021 - April 2023

- Collaboration in the development of an Angular web application for a towing and junkyard service provider, implementing functions such as real time service creation, development of push notifications with Socket IO, feedback on completed services, as well as forms and payments functionalities.
- Participation in the development of an Ionic mobile application and an Angular web page from scratch, focused on receiving services created by the app, filling out and sending forms (information and images) divided into steps by the tow truck driver, showing completed service to the web app and using SQLite for local data storage.
- Development of a normalized MYSQL database on client own server, and likewise creation of Node.js API with Express responsible for facilitating communication with the app and the web.
- Cooperation among team members and direct participation in gathering information with the client.

# Zangup | August 2020 - January 2021 | Ionic, Angular and Firebase

- Development of an Angular web app using of Angular Material and Firebase focused on presenting a product that was about to be released to the market called Squirk lubricant, implementing funcionalities such as sending and displaying product's reviews, sending a form for assistance in case of wanting to distribute the product or having problems with the product.
- Design and development a couple of mobile applications using Ionic + Angular from scratch, starting as initiative of Zangup for subsequent sale to multiple clients, designing and using Firebase as database.
- Development of an Angular web app using Angular Material to manage a mobile application by sharing data through Firebase.
- UI layout according to UX designs and combination with Bootstrap for responsive design.

# **EXOS** | August 2020 - February 2021 | Quasar and Vue

- Performance increase and optimization of Quasar (Vue) web application used in hotel sector as a solution of management issues of WiFi
  networks, facilitating the administration, control and support.
- Collaboration on some web projects to enhance the user interface design by adding responsiveness to adapt them to any size using Quasar's flex grid.
- · Participation in a project, developing views in web app for the banking sector, and consuming API's using Vuex.